-= 太空堡垒卡拉狄加 =-『 上集回顾 』
Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
那颗星球是科波
ELOSHA: This planet is Kobol.
人类的出生地
The birthplace of mankind.
组织陆地搜寻队  三架猛禽号
Organize a ground survey team. Three Raptors.
他们无处不在 先带我们离开这里
KARMA: They're everywhere! Get us out of here!
拉起来
TYROL: Pull it up!
爬下
CRASHDOWN: Get down!
卡拉狄加  我是阿波罗  星芭儿跳跃走了
APOLLO: Galactica. Apollo. Starbuck just jumped away.
如果你回到卡布里卡
ROSLIN: If you go back to Caprica
把箭给我带回来 我会为大家指明到达地球的道路
and bring me the arrow, it will show us the way to Earth.
星芭儿
Starbuck?
你要递出辞呈了
ADAMA: I'm terminating your presidency as of this moment.
要逮捕你  总统女士
TIGH: I am placing you under arrest, Madam President.
这是兵变  你是知道的
This is mutiny. You know that.
来 看一下即将降临的生命的脸庞吧
NO. 6: Come. See the face of the shape of things to come.
她是不是很漂亮呢  盖尤斯
Isn't she beautiful, Gaius?
我不是赛昂人
I'm not a Cylon.
这不是真的
This isn't happening.
天意难违  莎伦
CYLON BOOMER: You can't fight destiny, Sharon.
无论你做什么  都是命中注定
It catches up with you. No matter what you do.
让开
MAN: Make a hole!
急救员在哪里?卡托医生呢?
APOLLO: Where are the medics? Where's Doc Cottle?
不在船上  去舰队里巡查了长官  让开
ISHAY: Off-ship, on rounds in the fleet, sir. Stand clear!
起搏器 费舍尔军士前来报到 长官
FISCHER: Pressure. Sergeant Fischer reporting, sir.
拿到了? 起搏器  是
MAN: You got it? Pressure! FISCHER: Yeah.
放得太远…我在联系他
FISCHER: It's lodged too far. I'm calling for him.
他得用药  他得进行正压复苏
FISCHER: He's gotta be drugged. MAN: He's gotta be aggressive.
流血状况如何?  我们走
MAN: What's the status on the bleeding? Let's go.
可我们是否就在这里急救?
MAN: Are we supposed to do that here, though?
不 我们得尽快送他去医疗舱
FISCHER: No, we're gonna get him into med bay, as soon as possible.
我是你的新战友  比尔·阿达玛
I'm your new shipmate. Bill Adama.
索尔·泰
Saul Tigh.
他得了张力性气胸我必须对他胸部穿刺  减压
We've got tension pneumo. I'm gonna stick him and release the pressure.
他会没事的
FISCHER: He's gonna be okay.
怎么回事?  发生了什么事?
What's going on? What happened?
中士  把那东西关进禁闭室
Sergeant of the Guards, secure that thing in the brig.
是  长官  霍利斯  文斯勒  我们走  走!
Aye, sir. Hollis, Wenzler, let's go! Let's go!
不  等等...
BOOMER: No! Wait!
好  他还有呼吸
ISHAY: Okay, he's breathing.
我什么也没干
BOOMER: I didn't do anything!
立即把他送到医务室  密切监护
Let's get him down to sickbay, RFN.
不!
BOOMER: No!
沃莱瑞向老头子开了枪  什么?
Valerii shot the old man. What?
三  一  二...
BOOMER: Three-one...
她肯定是赛昂人
GAETA: She must be a Cylon.
上校在全权指挥  你是副指挥
The Colonel's in command. You're second.
让开!
ISHAY: Make a hole!
不!
BOOMER: No!
军士 逮捕阿达玛上尉
FISCHER: Sergeant, secure Captain Adama.
把他关进禁闭室
Put him in the brig!
上校!泰上校!
Colonel! Colonel Tigh!
走吧  我不
GUARD: Let's go! APOLLO: I didn't do it!
他是我父亲!
He's my father!
上校!  上校!
APOLLO: Colonel! KELLY: Colonel!
上校
APOLLO: Colonel.
这有可能是赛昂人进攻的前奏吗?
Could this be a prelude to a Cylon attack?
他们怎么会知道我们在哪里?
How would they know where we are?
可能是沃莱瑞告诉他们的  长官  什么?通过什么途径?
RACETRACK: Valerii could have told them, sir. What? How?
当我们在【基地之星】里面的时候
When we were aboard the Base Star,
她离开了猛禽号几分钟
she left the Raptor for a few minutes
回来的时候没戴头盔
and came back without her helmet.
她可能把一切事都告诉了赛昂人我们的位置  防御程度...
She might have told the Cylons everything, our position, defenses...
上校  赛鬼子们偷袭了我们的指挥官
KELLY: Colonel, the toasters have knocked out our CO.
这一定是更大的计划的一部分
This has gotta be part of a bigger plan.
我建议我们跳跃到应急备用坐标
I recommend we execute jump to emergency standby coordinates.
上校  我们已经找到卡托医生他在【希望之星】上
Colonel, I've located Doc Cottle. He's aboard the Rising Star.
雷达
GAETA: Dradis.
单个目标  赛昂【基地之星】方位4-8-7  弹回0-1-5
Single contact! Cylon Base Star, bearing 487-carom-015!
长官  我们不能留在这里
Sir, we can't stay here.
长官
Sir!
那你有什么计划?
ADAMA: So what's your plan here?
我个人倾向于先按你的计划行事
Personally, I tend to go with what you know
等有了更好的方案再说
till something better turns up.
长官
KELLY: Sir!
小杜  通知全体舰队
Dee, alert the fleet.
我们将立即跳跃到备用坐标
We are making an immediate jump to the emergency coordinates.
快去
Go!
长官  卡托医生还要15分钟才能赶来
Sir, Doc Cottle is still 15 minutes away.
他只能等到跳跃完毕后再来找我们了
He'll have to rejoin us on the other side of the jump.
长官  我们在科波上的人怎么办?
Sir, what about our people on the surface of Kobol?
如果他们还活着...就要等等了
If they're still alive, they'll have to wait.
超光速驱动器?
GAETA: FTL!
准备完毕!
DUALLA: Go.
导航控制?  准备完毕!
NavCon? DUALLA: Go.
各船请注意
Galactica to all vessels.
准备紧急超光速跳跃到逃亡坐标阿尔法
Prepare to make immediate FTL jump to escape coordinates Alpha.
重复  逃亡坐标阿尔法
I say again, escape coordinates Alpha.
按我口令计时
Clock will start on my mark.
计时开始
Mark!
上尉  他们把你怎么了?  出了什么事?
Captain, what have they done to you? What's going on?
我父亲遭到了枪击
My father's been shot.
什么?
What?
来人把这东西取下来  好吗?
Someone get this frakking thing off me, please?
我无权那么做
I'm not authorized to do that yet.
我他妈在栏杆后面啊!
I'm behind the frakking bars!
上尉
Captain,
你父亲的伤势有多重?
how bad is your father?
很重
Bad.
胸部中了两枪
Two bullets in the chest.
卡托医生在抢救他吗?
Is Dr. Cottle with him?
没有  卡托医生没在船上
No. Doc Cottle's not on board.
卡拉狄加  注意  舰队已离去
DUALLA: Attention, Galactica. Fleet is away.
准备跳跃  五  四
Stand by to jump in five, four,
三 二 一
three, two, one,
跳跃
jump!
跳跃完毕
Jump completed.
报告?
Report.
报告!?
Report!
雷达未发现目标
Dradis is empty. No contacts.
没有目标?  舰队到哪去了?
No contacts? Where's the fleet?
小杜!
Dee!
正在检查各频道
Checking all channels.
无殖民舰队信号
No Colonial signals.
他们不见了  长官
They're gone, sir.
她是不是很美呢  盖尤斯?
NO. 6: Isn't she beautiful, Gaius?
我想我一生之中都从未被如此深深触动过
GAIUS: I don't think I've ever been touched so deeply in my entire life.
你将是一名称职的好父亲
You're going to make a wonderful father.
是比喻吧
Speaking metaphorically, of course.
确实是这样
And literally.
她是我们的孩子  盖尤斯  我们的小女孩
She's our child, Gaius. Our little girl.
什么?
What?
你想抱一下她吗?
Do you want to hold her?
想!  当然想
Yes. Yes, of course I do.
可她不是真实存在的
But she's not real,
仅仅是...
any more than
这一切都不是...
any of this is
真实的
real.
她是真实的
She's real.
是吗?
She is?
她也许还没和你在一起  但很快...
She may not be with you yet, but she will be.
就会的
Soon.
我有点迷惑不解
I'm having a little difficulty.
我努力去领会
I'm trying to understand.
我想弄明白
I want to understand. I...
你是母亲
You're the mother.
而你是父亲
And you're the father.
我是父亲?
Am I the father?
什么?
Excuse me?
梦...
Dream.
很明显我是在做梦
I'm clearly having a dream.
我们要出发了  先生  起来吧
We're moving out, sir. Get up.
如果你这次不介意拿点东西的话...
And if you wouldn't mind carrying something this time,
那可太好了
that would be great.
这是奈法唑酮  有助于你的呼吸
This is Serisone. It should help you breathe a little easier.
放松
Take it easy.
几分钟内你就会感觉舒服些了
You'll be up, feeling better, in a few minutes.
请让一下  长官
Excuse me, sir.
我们要把你抬起来
We've got to get you up.
疼  我知道
It hurts. I know.
如果你不介意我问你我们这是要去哪里  克莱斯当?
If you don't mind me asking, where are we going, Crashdown?
树木林 我们可以藏起来
Tree line. We can hide
这样卡拉狄加派救援队来
but still see the crash site,
我们还可以看到
in case Galactica sends a rescue party.
卡拉狄加会派救援队的
Galactica will be sending a rescue party.
大家蹲下
CRASHDOWN: Everybody down!
怎么了?
CALLY: What was that?
是赛昂人吗?
That Cylons?
希利克丝  收拾弹药
Seelix, grab the ammo.
交错队型  我作先头
Staggered formation, I'll take point.
上士  你断后
Chief, you're bringing up the rear.
准备暗中行动  各位
Be ready to double-time it, people!
一  二  三!
One, two, three!
中尉  我认为在我们撤退之前要再检查一遍补给
El-tee, I think we should double-check the supplies before we bug out.
抱歉  上士  我们没时间了  如果那是一架飞船
Sorry, Chief, we don't have the time. If that's an aircraft turbine,
那它随时会发现我们
they're gonna be on us any moment!
中尉  我们要确保带上了所有东西
El-tee, we've gotta make sure we have everything!
没时间了  上士
We don't have the time, Chief!
天杀的!
Damn it.
该死!
Gods damn it.
怎么回事  索尔?舰队到哪去了?
What's going on, Saul? Where's the fleet?
不清楚  他们跳跃到了另一个位置
We don't know. They jumped to another location.
你裤子上都是血
You've got blood on your pants.
怎么会这样?
Why would they do that?
每次我们为了校正惯性推进力
Every watch, we update our emergency
都要通过新星装置
jump calculations with new star fixes
来计算出我们的跳跃能量参数的
to compensate for inertial drift.
然后我们发送给舰队内其他飞船
And then we transmit them to the rest of the fleet.
这一次我们的更新了可他们的却没有
This time, ours were updated, but theirs weren't.
盖塔本该发送给其他飞船的
Gaeta was supposed to transmit them to the rest of the fleet.
那就是盖塔的责任
So it's Gaeta's fault.
那孩子都蒙了  手忙脚乱的
The kid was overwhelmed. He had his hands full.
那就算是吧  这事听来很糟糕...
If you say so. It sounds like a pretty big screw-up to me.
在下达跳跃命令前我本该亲自检查一次!
I should have checked before I gave the order to jump!
这一点也不像你  索尔  你从不让队员放松一丝警惕
This doesn't sound like you, Saul. You don't let people slide.
时刻督促他们
You bust their ass.
如果比尔没能挺过来...
Now if Bill doesn't make it...
他能挺过来
He'll make it.
如果不行  这就是你的船了  由你指挥
If he doesn't, this will be your ship. Your command.
我说的是你...
All I'm saying is you need to be...
这是比尔·阿达玛的船!
This is Bill Adama's ship.
这是他的战舰
This is his command.
在这船上他的命令依旧是神圣不可违抗的
His orders are still the word of the gods on this ship.
这我们要弄清楚
Just so we're clear.
在阿达玛有生之年都要由他来指挥
This will be Adama's command until the day he dies.
我们不会让他离我们而去
And we are not going to let him die.
同心协力!
So say we all.
ALL: So say we all.
稍息!
As you were.
我们怎么才能找到舰队?
So how do we find the fleet?
如果我们跳跃回原始坐标
If we jump back to our original coordinates,
我们的导航计算机可以凭借星际装置
our Nav computers can use those star fixes
生成最佳解决方案
to generate a best-fit solution
从而显示出舰队当前位置
giving the fleet's current position.
赛昂人正在那里等着我们
The Cylons are waiting for us back there.
一旦回去后要计算多久?
How long will it take to calculate once we get back there?
如果我们关闭所有设备...
If we shut down all other functions,
12小时吧
12 hours.
我们不可能与赛昂【基地之星】对峙12小时
TIGH: There's no way we can hold off a Cylon Base Star for 12 hours.
我们必须跳跃回去不能留在这里
We have got to jump back. We can't stay here.
瑟瑞丝中尉一旦从卡布里卡获得那只箭
Lieutenant Thrace won't be able to find us
就找不到我们了
once she retrieves the arrow from Caprica.
除非她得到了那只箭
If she retrieves the arrow.
她会得到那只箭
She'll retrieve the arrow.
上尉  你必须重返岗位
Captain, you've got to get reinstated.
回到作战信息中心
You've got to get back to CIC.
谴责我  把责任推到我的身上做任何必要的事
You've got to denounce me, disavow me, do whatever you need to do.
泰上校在没有你父亲的情况下无法独自找到舰队
Colonel Tigh cannot relocate this fleet on his own without your father.
泰不会放我出去
Tigh's not letting me out of here.
我用枪指了他的头
I put a gun to his head.
他不会善罢甘休的
He won't forget that anytime soon.
把你牵扯进来真的很抱歉  上尉
I am so sorry that I got you into this, Captain.
不  不用道歉  我当时知道自己在做什么
No, don't apologize. I knew what I was doing. I...
但我这么做不是为了你  我为了…
And I didn't do it for you. I did it for...
结果是...徒劳的
Well, actually, I did it for nothing, turns out.
不是那样  你选择了立场
That's not true. You took a stand.
可看看我们现在的境地
And now look at us.
小心脚下  好吧
TYROL: Watch your foot. SEELIX: Okay.
大家休息5分钟
Everyone take five.
给我医药箱  医药箱呢?
Give me the med kit. Where's the med kit?
你怎么样?
How you doing?
怎么样  兄弟?
Hey, how you doing, buddy?
挺好的
Good.
在听鸟叫
Just listening to the birds.
我真该死
I'll be damned.
我都记不起上次听到鸟叫是什么时候了
I don't remember the last time I heard birds.
放松  好吗?
Take it easy, okay?
该死
Damn it.
我们没有奈法唑酮了
We're out of Serisone.
托特  给她拿另一个医药箱
Tarn, get the other med kit.
什么另一个医药箱?
What other med kit?
别他妈告诉我没有  我们可从船里抢出了两个医药箱
Don't frakking tell me. We pulled two med kits from the ship.
我告诉过你要留心照看着
I told you to keep an eye on both of them.
我只看到一个  长官  有两个!
I only saw the one, sir. There were two!
对不起  长官我不记得你告诉我--
I'm sorry, sir, but I don't remember you telling me...
我告诉过你!
Well, I did!
长官  他的肺部充满液体
Sir, his lungs are filling up with fluid.
如果不尽快搞到奈法唑酮  他就挺不住了
If he doesn't get more Serisone soon, he's not gonna make it.
好吧 好吧 托特
Okay. All right, Tarn.
你忘了医药箱  所以就要你去拿回来
You forgot the med kit, so you're gonna have to go back and get it.
拿一支步枪  三夹子弹  一个水壶
Take a rifle, three clips of ammo, and a canteen.
什么?
What?
快去!
Move.
凯莉  过来
Cally, come here.
把守后面
Watch the rear.
中尉  你不能让他单独去
El-tee, you can't send him alone.
你在置疑我的命令吗  上士?
You questioning my orders, Chief?
不  我只是指出你计划中的不足
No, I'm just pointing out a flaw in your plan.
没有其他意思  凯莉和我和他一起去
It doesn't need to be any bigger than that. Cally and I can go with him.
好  好吧
All right, fine.
可你能照看好凯莉吗?
But would you look out for Cally?
凯莉  把步枪给我
Cally, give me the rifle.
我们三个去  放下那东西  放下你的背包
We three go. Leave that, leave your backpack.
取下备用武器
TYROL: Sidearms out.
托特  你在中间  把守后面
Tarn, you're bringing up the rear.
只用眼睛和耳朵
In the middle, eyes and ears.
她的思想正被下载到另一副躯体之中
Her consciousness is being downloaded into another body right now.
她醒来后就会告诉其他人我们的方位
And when she wakes up, she'll tell them exactly where we are.
她说的对  我们不能在此逗留
She's right. We can't stay here.
她说的对  是吗?
She's right, huh?
赛昂人莎伦说的对
Sharon the Cylon is right.
听赛昂人莎伦准没错
Let's all just listen to Sharon the Cylon,
按她说的做  因为那主意不错
do whatever she says, 'cause that's a good idea.
卡拉  有她在我才活到了今天
Hey, Kara, she helped me get this far.
好  我懂  我懂  西洛
Okay, I get it. I get it, Helo.
你我回头想想  我懂
You and I go way back, so I get it.
好  我记得你对她的感情
All right, I remember how you felt about her.
但那不是真正的莎伦
But that is not the real Sharon.
只是个低贱的复制体
That is some cheap knock-off copy.
我不是复制体  我是莎伦
I'm not a copy. I'm Sharon.
我记得当初第一次见到你那时候的情景  星芭儿
I remember the first day I met you, Starbuck.
你因为吃了过期的牡蛎
You were puking your guts out in the head
结果吐得昏天黑地
because you'd eaten bad oysters on...
别说了!
Don't do that. Hey!
我不喜欢听  我也不喜欢你
I don't like it, and I don't like you.
所以就最好给我闭嘴
So the best thing you can do is just keep your damn mouth shut.
星芭儿  把枪放下  看在上帝的份上
Starbuck, put it down, for gods' sakes.
你想让我怎样  西洛?
What do you want from me, Helo?
她是赛昂人
She's a Cylon.
你被骗了
You've been had.
我们都被骗了
We've been had.
所以要我怎样  该对她好吗?
So what, I'm just supposed to be nice to her
就因为她说她怀孕了?
because she says she's pregnant?
让开
Get out of the way.
不
No.
卡尔  别以为我不会--
Karl, do not think that I will not shoot...
我不会让你杀了她
I'm not gonna let you kill her!
知道吗?  她怀了我的孩子
Okay? She's carrying my child!
我的天  男人有时真是傻的可以
My gods, men are so painfully stupid sometimes!
你怎么知道?!
How do you know that?
我知道  好吗?她没说谎!
I know, all right? She's not lying.
他们所说的全是谎言  西洛
They lie about everything, Helo.
他们生来就是说谎的
Their entire existence is a lie.
他们不是人类  西洛  是机器
They're not human, Helo. They're machines.
人和机器不可能生育
You can't have a baby with a machine!
我都不知道该怎么和你说了  知道吗?
I don't know what to tell you, okay?
可我相信她
But I believe her.
这种感觉难以描述  我们在一起很长时间
It's hard to describe. We've been together a long time.
我知道她是什么
I mean, I know what she is,
但她和其他赛昂人不一样
but she is not like the others.
不一样!
She is not.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no!
那贱人偷了我的战机
Bitch took my ride.
好吧 继续
MAN: Yeah, go ahead.
他怎么样了?
How's he doing?
子弹击穿了他的脾
Well, the bullets tore up his spleen.
他的血压太低了
His blood pressure is way down.
必须有人给他止血
Somebody needs to get in there and stop the bleeding
否则我们会失去他
or we'll lose him.
那你的计划是什么?
ADAMA: So what's your plan?
还没一个象样的
TIGH: Don't really have one.
我要回去驾驶战机了
I'm getting back in the cockpit.
我要重返舰队
I'm getting back into my fleet.
我希望你和我一起去  索尔
I want you to come with me, Saul.
你真以为我们可以返回舰队?
You really believe that we can get back in the fleet?
恩  是的
Yeah, I do.
卡托医生还要多久才能到?
How long until Doc Cottle's aboard?
不知道
I don't know.
要等一段时间了
It's gonna be a while.
他的时间不多了  长官
He doesn't have much time, sir.
要你亲自上阵了
You're gonna have to go in yourself.
我?  我只是一名急救员
Me? I'm just a medic.
今天你就是一名医生
Today, you're a doctor.
上校
Colonel.
打开牢房
TIGH: Open the cell.
指挥官怎么样了?
How's the Commander?
你把一切弄得一团糟  如果这是你想知道的话
You've bungled the job, if that's what you're asking.
就是说他还活着  谢天谢地
Then he's alive. Thank the gods.
我们的驾驶员中还有多少人是赛昂人?
How many of our pilots were Cylons?
不知道
I don't know.
谁下的命令让你去杀老头子?
Who gave the order to shoot the old man?
没人
No one.
别多想了  你他妈的懦夫
Just get it over with, you frakking coward!
把枪给我  给我!
Give me your sidearm! Give me your gun!
是  长官
GUARD: Yes, sir.
开枪吧  别犹豫
Just shoot me. Get it over with.
好  过去看一下
TYROL: Hey, Tarn. Go up, take a look.
如果没在那里  就在猛禽号里了
If it's not there, it's at the Raptor.
我们还得继续向前走
We'll have to move up more.
找到了  上士
I got it, Chief.
好  快离开这鬼地方
TYROL: All right, let's get the hell out of here.
托特在前
Tarn on point.
快走  走
Let's go! Go, go, go, go, go.
没道理
CALLY: This makes no sense.
为什么你们忘了带医药箱而却要我来提着
Why am I carrying the med kit when you forgot it?
首先  那是中尉的箱子
First of all, that's the El-tee's kit.
其次  我在前面
Secondly, I'm on point.
随便啦
Whatever.
好了  孩子们  够了
All right, children, that's enough.
我告诉你吧  凯莉  如果能让你好受些
Tell you what, Cally. If it makes you feel any better,
下周我让他和你一起去机库拖地
I'll put him on hangar deck mop-up duty with you for the next week.
这才对嘛  为什么?
CALLY: Now you're talking. TARN: For what?
如果有人该去拖地  那肯定是中尉
If anybody should have mop duty, it's the El-tee.
快  爬下
Go! Go! Get down!
在山上
Top of the ridge!
凯莉  拿步枪掩护我
Cally! Take the rifle and cover me!
压制火力
Drastic fire!
好  等我
Okay, okay. Wait for me.
等我  好吗?
Wait for me, all right?
开火  开火
Go! Go! Go!
在那儿别动
Stay there! Don't move!
别动  我去救你  别动
I'm coming for you. Don't move!
上士
Chief!
我来了  凯莉  掩护我
TYROL: Cally! Help me out here, Cally!
凯莉  开火  开火
Give me fire! Cally, go! Go!
他们藏起来了  上士我看不到他们
There's no need, Chief! I can't see them!
掩护我  托特  别动  别动
TYROL: Cover me! Tarn, stay down! Stay down!
上士
CALLY: Chief!
Come on, Chief!
你没事  没事  没事
You're okay. You're okay. It's okay.
上来  到我背上来
It's okay. Get on my back.
到我背上来  上来
Get on my back. Get on me, get on me!
上士
CALLY: Chief!
上士  停下来  他们没追来
CALLY: Chief, stop. They're not following us anymore.
那里  上士
Cally, there... Chief...
我知道你受伤了  兄弟  没关系
I know you're hit, buddy. It's okay.
我马上为你检查伤口  我把他放这里了  小莉
I'm gonna check you right now. I'm gonna put him here, Cal.
这里  蹲下  就待在这里好吗
Here. Lay down. You're gonna stay right here, okay?
我马上为你看看伤口
I'm gonna check you right now. Let's just try...
不太坏  不太坏
It's not that bad. It's not that bad.
凯莉  看守山头
Cally, check the ridge.
我想回家
I wanna go home.
我知道  我知道  我们回家
TYROL: I know. I know. We're going home.
我们回家  好吗?
We're going home, okay? Okay.
带我走
TARN: Take me with you.
没关系  没关系  别睡着
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay. Stay with me.
看着我  看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
别睡着  别睡着
Stay with me. Stay with me.
别睡着  醒醒
Here, be with me. Be with me, come on.
别睡着  喂…
Come on. Hey. Hey.
上士
CALLY: Chief?
上士  我们得走了  离开这里
Chief, we gotta go. We gotta go.
上士
Chief?
看看  看看  你他妈个混蛋
Gods damn this stupid frakked-up crap!
上士  现在瑟赛纳斯需要我们
Chief, Socinus needs us now. Come on.
来吧  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
错不在你  中尉
Not your fault, Lieutenant.
至少在我看来不是
Not from where I was standing.
我是值班军官
I was the OOD.
当时一片混乱  长官
It was crazy in there, sir.
不要自责
You can't blame yourself.
我们跳跃回到上一次的坐标
So, we jump back to the last coordinates,
但我们把超光速引擎的计算机与导航检修组
but we network the FTL computer with the Nav, DC,
消防组的计算机联网
and fire control computers.
一旦连接后
Once they're linked,
我们只需10分钟便可完成计算
we'll only need 10 minutes to complete the calculations.
不是吧
You can't be serious.
老头子可不会同意这么干  上校
The old man would never do this, Colonel.
这船上禁止连接计算机网络
No computer networks on his ship.
我承认  长官
I acknowledge that, sir.
但我可以设计出一款防火墙来为我们争取更多的时间
But I can devise a software firewall that will buy us more time.
真的?你能在软件方面比赛昂人棋高一招吗?
Really? You're going to out-think the Cylons at computer software?
长官  如果我们不这么做我们永远也不会找到舰队了
Sir, if we don't do this, we're never gonna find the fleet.
更不用提在指挥官去世之前了
Certainly not before the Commander dies.
这仍旧是老头子的命令
This is still the old man's command.
我们不能违抗
We can't do something he'd oppose,
尤其是拿整艘船来冒险
especially when it puts the entire ship at risk.
我是副长
This is the XO.
为跳跃做准备
Begin jump prep.
这是...我的命令
Those are my orders.
这小子重返舰队了
The kid is back in the fleet!
比尔  我们来说实话吧
Bill, let's have the truth.
你怎么做到的?
So how did you do it?
怎么从他妈的那个货船脱身的?
How'd you get off this frakking freighter?
靠关系  安妮的父亲有一个朋友在国防分委会
Connections. Anne's father has a friend on the Defense Subcommittee.
新老婆驾到了
So the new wife comes through.
但愿我也能找个有关系的老婆
I wish I had in-laws with pull.
给我几年时间...
Give me a couple of years.
我会有些关系的
I'll have some pull.
你看着吧
You watch me.
总有一天我会有一艘属于我自己的太空堡垒
I'll have my own Battlestar one day.
请开门
GUARD: Open up, please.
好  我向你发誓
All right. You have my parole.
在我当值的时候  我不会试图释放她
When I'm on duty, I'll make no attempt to free her or sow insurrection
或是在船员之间煽动叛乱
among the crew.
下班以后我直接到牢房里报道
When I'm not on duty, I'll report directly back to this cell.
飞行前简令正在预备室进行
Pre-flight brief is underway in the Ready Room.
对了
Right.
祝你好运  上尉
ROSLIN: Good hunting, Captain.
谢谢您  总统女士
Thank you, Madam President.
上校  一旦你找到了舰队
Colonel, once you find the fleet,
我想和你谈话
I'd like to have a word with you.
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
你顶撞了老头子  结果你输了
You went up against the old man and you lost.
我们跳跃到那里  与赛昂人相持
We jump in, we hold off the Cylons,
我们计算数据  然后跳跃离开
we crunch the numbers, and we jump out.
就这样  简单任务
That's it. Simple plan.
做起来却不简单
Not so simple to do.
计算机已经联网
GAETA: Computers have been networked.
准备完毕  长官
The board is green, sir.
各工作站报告准备好跳跃
All stations report ready to jump.
超光速引擎就位
MAN: FTL go!
防火墙准备好了吗?
That software firewall ready?
我已经尽最大努力了  长官  波塔尔博士在这里就好了
GAETA: Best I can make it, sir. I wish Dr. Baltar was here.
去他的  你早就可以
To hell with that. I'll take your work
赶超那个靠不住的混蛋
over that shifty son of a bitch any day.
启动超光速引擎 预备
DUALLA: Speeding up FTL drive. Stand by!
五  四  三  二
In five, four, three, two,
跳跃
jump!
跳跃完毕
Jump completed.
报告?
Report.
雷达发现多个目标
GAETA: Multiple dradis contacts.
赛昂【基地之星】和多架赛昂突袭机
Cylon Base Star, and multiple Cylon Raiders,
方位4-8-7  弹回2-2-1
bearing 487-carom-221.
中尉
Lieutenant!
正在进行计算...
Computations underway.
7分钟内就能测算出舰队的位置
We'll be able to plot the fleet's position in seven minutes.
让我们把这些疯子打个稀巴烂
Let's get these suckers!
弗莱波  知道我们在打赌吧?
Hey, Flyboy, you know we got a pool going, right?
趁星芭儿开小差的时候看谁杀的最多
To see who gets the most kills now that's Starbuck's AWOL.
你我都清楚我会是终结者
We know I'm gonna clean up.
弗莱波  闭嘴  注意这不是模拟训练
Flyboy, shut up and focus. This is not a simulation.
收到
Roger that.
他的心跳停止了
KIM: His heart stopped.
心脏起搏器  快!
Defib now!
电力不稳  电力组在急救站
KIM: Power's unstable. The battery units are at the aid stations.
那就给我拿把刀
Well, then get me a knife.
自由射击
Weapons free.
锁定目标开火!
And open racks and engage!
蝮蛇21 我就在你后面
PILOT: Viper two-one, I'm right behind your tail.
它们来了
Here it comes.
赛昂人在攻击我们的网络
The Cylons are hacking our network.
想要访问我们的网关
They're attempting to access our gateway.
竞赛开始了
Now it's a race.
我们又干掉三个 记下来
PILOT: We've got three more. Spike that, spike that.
又干掉四个
We have four more.
渗透过第一层防火墙了
GAETA: First firewall penetrated.
阿尔法  我们发现了一架可疑战机
APOLLO: Sierra-Alpha. We got a new bogey.
那是什么东西?
HOTDOG: What is that thing?
不知道  可不管是什么它都在向卡拉狄加袭来
I don't know, but whatever it is, it's bearing on Galactica.
我们要把它干掉
We've got to take it out!
阿波罗  热狗  防御
Apollo, Hotdog, defensive.
三架在右侧  五架在两点位置
Three right, five at two.
泰丽  热狗  交给我吧
Tally, Hotdog! Kat, on me!
收到  我和你并肩作战  老大
KAT: Roger that. I'm with you, leader.
和我一起祈祷好吗?
Will you pray with me?
救助我们  科波之主
Help us, Lords of Kobol.
救助您的先知劳拉引领我们踏上正义的道路
Help your prophet, Laura, guide us to the path of righteousness
我们就可以--
that we might...
摧毁我们的敌人
That we might destroy our enemies.
让我们走上正义的道路
Let us walk the path of righteousness
愿您保佑我们直到平安
and lift our faces unto your goodness.
救助我们避过凶险
Help us turn away from the calls of the wicked
向我们展现您一定会带领我们脱离苦难
and show us the knowledge of your certain salvation.
请听我们的祷告
We offer this prayer...
计算完成56%
GAETA: Calculations at 56%.
已突破第二道防火墙
Second firewall's been breached!
该死!
APOLLO: Damn it!
干  他们真快第三道防火墙已被摧毁
GAETA: Frak, they're fast. Third firewall down!
阿波罗  接近卡拉狄加高射炮垒
KAT: Apollo, approaching Galactica's flack barrier.
赛昂人目标在大炮火力范围内
Cylon target within gun range.
击中机翼了
APOLLO: Wind it!
阿波罗  我们快进入卡拉狄加火力圈了
KAT: Apollo, we're straying into Galactica's engagement zone!
就快了
I'm almost there. I'm almost there.
差一点  来啊!
I'm almost there. Come on!
靠 靠
Frak! Frak!
该死!
APOLLO: Damn it!
我本可以击中它!
Had it!
进入预定位置 火力退敌
APOLLO: Plan in position for a strafing run!
阿波罗报告右舷飞行吊舱遭受撞击
Apollo reports impact on the starboard flight pod.
飞行吊舱减压
APOLLO: We've got a decompression in the flight pod.
没有发生爆炸 没有火灾
No explosion, no fire.
重复  没有火灾
Repeat, no fire.
没有火灾
No fire!
80%了  快了
GAETA: 80%! Almost there.
他们通过了第四层防火墙
They're through the fourth firewall.
还有一层就到达我们主机了
One left till they've accessed our mainframe.
混蛋!
Frakker.
那个本来是我的  是我的
That's mine. That was mine.
我们得到了舰队的方位
We have a solution for the fleet's position!
断开网络连接
Break the network!
抓紧
PILOT: Hang tight.
当然 先生们 当然
Sure can, gentlemen. Sure can.
已断开
Network is broken!
计算机恢复成局域控制
Computers restored to local control!
告诉蝮蛇驾驶员返回母舰
Tell the Vipers to get back aboard.
我们今天真是幸运
We're getting awful lucky today.
准备跳跃
Prepare to jump!
蝮蛇战机登舰完毕  长官
DUALLA: Vipers aboard, sir.
预备  5  4  3  2…
Stand by in five, four, three, two,
跳跃
jump.
跳跃完毕
Jump completed.
报告?
Report.
母舰周围多个目标
GAETA: Multiple contacts, round the board.
殖民者的应答器  长官  我们找到他们了!
Colonial transponders, sir. We found them!
凯利上尉
Captain Kelly.
盖塔中尉  长官
Lieutenant Gaeta. Sir.
小杜
Dee, contact the Rising Star.
联络【希望之星】告诉卡托立即到这来
Tell Cottle to get his ass over here, ASAP.
干的不错
Hell of a job.
从现在开始  别再让我做心脏按压了
From now on, no more heart massages for me.
我以后就负责药片和灌肠剂
I'm sticking to pills and enemas.
长官
Sir.
情况如何?
Let's hear it.
我设法止了血  但...他仍旧情况危急
Well, I managed to stop the bleeding, but he's still critical.
医生正在赶来
TIGH: Doc's on his way.
能听见我说话吗  比尔?
Can you hear me, Bill?
走开
Go away!
泰上尉  我是海军宪兵
WATKINS: Captain Tigh? This is Shore Patrol.
霍金斯中士  长官  请开门
Sergeant Watkins, sir. Open up, please.
阿达玛少校的问候
Major Adama's compliments.
他希望我来通知您
He wishes me to inform you,
您已经被重新录用进殖民舰队
you've been reinstated in the Colonial Fleet
军衔为上尉
with the rank of Captain.
阿达玛少校?
Major Adama?
欢迎回归舰队  长官
Welcome back to the Fleet, sir.
我马上就来  中士
I'll be right with you, Sergeant.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你就不该再让我回来工作
You never should've brought me back in the service.
如果你对我放任不管
If you'd just let me be,
我可能就和别人在卡布里卡上死了
I'd have died back there on Caprica along with everyone else,
我还心满意足
and been happier for it.
我不想指挥
I don't want a command.
我以前也没想过
I never did.
你现在可别在我面前就这么走了
Don't you dare die on me now.